Guide to the Mark Penn polling data collection, 1988-2008, 2019 MS2348
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Mark Penn digital polling data collection and oral history
1988-2008, 2019
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Penn, Mark J
Cornfield, Michael, 1955 -
MS2348
33 digital object(s) 33 digital files
In 1975, Penn and Doug Schoen, founded the polling firm Penn Schoen Berland. Early clients included Ed Koch, Luis Herrera Campins in Venezuela, Menachem Begin for re-election as prime minister of Israel, President Bill Clinton, and British prime minister Tony Blair. Penn was a chief strategist and pollster in the Hillary Clinton 2008 presidential campaign. He has worked for Microsoft and is currently President and Managing Partner of The Stagwell Group, a private equity fund focused on the marketing services industry. This collection contains digital files with subject content of polling data for William Jefferson Clinton's presidency, the 2008 Hillary Clinton presidential campaign, and Labour Party polling as well as speeches, and debate preparation content. The materials cover 1988-2005 with the bulk of the data falling between 1996-2007. In addition, there is an oral history conducted in 2019 by GW professor Dr. Michael Cornfield with Mark Penn.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains digital files with subject content of polling data for William Jefferson Clinton's presidency, the 2008 Hillary Clinton presidential campaign, and Labour Party polling as well as speeches, and debate preparation content. The materials cover 1988-2005 with the bulk of the data falling between 1996-2007. These twenty-eight original bound volumes and binders of weekly strategy session agendas (polling data, media records, policy discussion) were created by Mark Penn (DNC Pollster who worked with Bill Clinton during his years in office). In addition, is an oral history conducted in 2019 by GW professor Dr. Michael Cornfield with Mark Penn.
Custodial History
Per the agreement with Mark Penn the bound volumes were provided to GW for digitization and then were returned to Mr. Penn.
Biographical / Historical
Mark Penn grew up in Riverdale, NY. He graduated from the elite Horace Mann School in New York City in 1972 and Harvard University in 1976 with a degree political science. In 1975, Penn and Doug Schoen, founded the polling firm Penn Schoen Berland. Early clients included Ed Koch, Luis Herrera Campins in Venezuela, Menachem Begin for re-election as prime minister of Israel, President Bill Clinton, and British prime minister Tony Blair. Penn was a chief strategist and pollster in the Hillary Clinton 2008 presidential campaign.
In July 2012, Penn was named Corporate Vice President for Strategic and Special Projects at Microsoft Corporation. In 2015, Penn left Microsoft and created his own company called The Stagwell Group dealing with advertising and public relations. He is currently president and managing partner in this private equity fund focused on the marketing services industry.
Conditions Governing Access
These files are available for research. At this time the pdf copies of the polling data do not meet GW University standards for accessibility compliance and have not been uploaded to the Internet. These files are available for use in our reading room and also researchers may ask for remote access copies by contacting Special Collection staff. The oral history has four parts and for the recordings for which the SCRC has a transcript the recording and transcript have been uploaded to the Internet. For part 3 of there recording please ask to listen in the reading room or for a copy to be provided to you as a remote user.
Arrangement
Organized in three series: HRC data index [Hillary Clinton polling data], William Jefferson Clinton polling data and Labour Party polling data, and Oral history [Mark Penn and Dr. Michael Cornfield]
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mark Penn February 27 2018 and September 9 2019 (accession 2019.010)
United States--Politics and government; Exit polling (Elections); Public opinion polls; Voting research
- HRC data index [Hillary Clinton polling data], 1992-2008; MS2348 Series 1
  Conditions Governing Access
  These files are available for research. At this time the pdf copies of the polling data do not meet GW University standards for accessibility compliance and have not been uploaded to the Internet. These files are available for use in our reading room and also researchers may ask for remote access copies by contacting Special Collection staff.
  Arrangement
  Arrangement maintains the original order with color-coded binders and separate bound volumes.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains digital files with polling data gathered for Hillary Clinton's 2008 presidential campaign. Some of this data is from previous campaigns and polls and was used as part of the campaign. These materials date from 1988-2008.
  - Yellow Binder 1.1: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): Iowa Tracker August 2007, National Tracker, Democratic Primary and General Election, July 2007, and Iowa Microtargeting Executive Summary July 2007, 2007 July - August; MS2348 Series 1
  - Yellow Binder 1.2: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): New Hampshire Tracker June 2007, National Tracker and Book Response June 2007, and South Carolina African American Poll May 2007, 2007 May - June; MS2348 Series 1
  - Yellow Binder 1.3: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): New Hampshire Microtargeting May 2007, National Tracker May 2007, and National Tracker April 2007, 2007 April - May; MS2348 Series 1
  - Yellow Binder 1.4: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): Primary State Polling South Caroline April 2007, Primary State Polling California April 2007, Primary State Polling Florida April 2007, Primary State Polling Iowa April 2007, and Primary State Polling Texas April 2007, 2007 April; MS2348 Series 1
  - Yellow Binder 1.5: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): National Heath Care Poll March 2007, National Tracker February 2007, and National Iraq Flash Poll February 2007, 2007 February - March; MS2348 Series 1
  - Yellow Binder 1.6: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): National Flash Poll February 2007, New Hampshire Benchmark January 2007, and Iowa Mini Flash Poll and Agenda January 2007, 2007 January - February; MS2348 Series 1
  - Yellow Binder 2: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): HRC National Polls, 2007 July 31; MS2348 Series 1
  - Yellow Binder 3: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): HRC National Polls, 2007 November; MS2348 Series 1
  - Yellow Binder 4: Polling Info (2008 Presidential Election): PSB National Polls (For HRC), 2007 January - August; MS2348 Series 1
  - Purple Binder 1: Misc. Materials (2008 Presidential Election): Hillary Clinton Debate Book, Circa 2007-2008; MS2348 Series 1
  - Purple Binder 2: Misc. Materials (2008 Presidential Election): Hillary Clinton Speeches/ Adwork/ Press Conferences, Circa 2007-2008; MS2348 Series 1
  - Purple Binder 3: Misc. Materials (2008 Presidential Election): Hillary Clinton Strategy Memos, Circa 2007-2008; MS2348 Series 1
  - Blue Binder 1: Polling Info (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): 1996 National Exit Polls, MS2348 Series 1
  - Blue Binder 2: Polling Info (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): Misc. Exit polls, 1996-1998; MS2348 Series 1
  - Blue Binder 3: Polling Info (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): Gore Polling memos, Undated; MS2348 Series 1
  - Red Binder 1: Misc. Materials (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): Democratic Convention Summarys, 1988-1998; MS2348 Series 1
  - Red Binder 2: Misc. Materials (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): '92 Presidential Debates Handbook, Circa 1992; MS2348 Series 1
  - Red Binder 3: Misc. Materials (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): "Hillary Clinton Senate Race Bible - Part I: the Old Testament (pre Lazio)", Undated; MS2348 Series 1
  - Red Binder 4: Misc. Materials (Pre-2008 Presidential Election): William J. Clinton Presidential History Project briefing materials, Undated; MS2348 Series 1
  - Bound volume: Polls of Senator Hillary Clinton, 1999 April - December; MS2348 Series 1
  - Bound volume: Polls of Senator Hillary Clinton, 2000 January - May; MS2348 Series 1
  - Bound volume: Polls of Senator Hillary Clinton, 2000 June - August; MS2348 Series 1
  - Bound volume: Polls of Senator Hillary Clinton, 2000 September - November; MS2348 Series 1
- William Jefferson Clinton polling data and Labour Party polling data, 1997-2005; MS2348 Series 2
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains digital files of bound volumes of William Jefferson Clinton polling data and Labour Party polling data. The materials date from 1997-2005.
  - Bound volume: Polls of President William Jefferson Clinton, 1997 January - December; MS2348 Series 2
  - Bound volume: Polls of President William Jefferson Clinton, 1998 January - May; MS2348 Series 2
  - Bound volume: Polls of President William Jefferson Clinton, 1998 June - December; MS2348 Series 2
  - Bound volume: Polls of President William Jefferson Clinton, 1999 January - December; MS2348 Series 2
  - Bound volume: Polling: The Labour Party, 2004-2005; MS2348 Series 2
- Oral history [Mark Penn and Dr. Michael Cornfield], 2019 May 15; Series 3
  This series contains an oral history conducted by Dr. Michael Cornfield, Associate Professor and Research Director of the Global Center for Political Management, George Washington University with Mark Penn. The interivew took place on May 15, 2019.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  These recordings and transcripts were provided to the SCRC by Michael Cornfield. The file transfer included transcripts of parts 1, 2, and 4 and recordings of parts 2, 3, 4.
  These files are open for use. The oral history has four parts and for the recordings for which the SCRC has a transcript the recording and transcript have been uploaded to the Internet. For part 3 of there recording please ask to listen in the reading room or for a copy to be provided to you as a remote user.
  - Recordings, Series 3
    - Mark Penn interview (part 2), 2019 May 15; Series 3
    - Mark Penn interview (part 3), 2019 May 15; Series 3
      This recording is available for using in the SCRC reading room or by requesting a digital copy from staff. At this time we are unable to upload this recording because we do not have a transcript.
    - Mark Penn interview (part 4), 2019 May 15; Series 3
  - Transcriptions, Series 3
    - Mark Penn interview transcript (part 1), 2019 May 15; Series 3
    - Mark Penn interview transcript (part 2), 2019 May 15; Series 3
    - Mark Penn interview transcript (part 4), 2019 May 19; Series 3